Hey cool kids, emergency video for anybody protesting on their college campus.
This is me, 10 years ago, protesting on my college campus in grad school after Michael Brown was killed.
Number one, shut up.
It's a given not to talk to police, but don't talk to administrators either.
They want to meet with us. I'm sure they do.
They had their chance to meet with you, and they sick the police on you instead.
Never forget that.
Two, discuss nothing important in chats.
Discord, any kind of group message like that, don't.
Check-ins and general information only there.
Planning should always take place in person with no phones present.
Speaking of, number three, write everything down.
If it's not written down, it didn't happen.
This is a good job for somebody to do that cannot be out on the front lines for whatever reason.
Four, find an adult to your adult and tell them where you are, what you're doing, and when you get home.
There are some things in movement spaces that require a level of secrecy.
Your safety is not one of them.
Next, for now, we suggest that you keep protests campus-specific because different states, different counties, different institutions have different rules about when you are and are not considered a student.
And being a student, at least for now, provides you with a bubble of semi-protection.
If you are an amateur protester or demonstrator, you are inside before dark.
Do you hear me?
You are inside before dark.
Incorporate art, dance, and joy into your activism as much as you can.
Rest and hydrate.
Because I have been saying this for years, you get no extra points for running yourself into the ground.
One more time, you get no extra points for running yourself into the ground.
If I was still teaching on a college campus right now, I would cancel whatever lesson I was doing and have my students read these three things.
And you should read them too.
There are three kinds of protests that America has and always will use its full weight to try and stop.
Labor protests, protests for black rights, and anti-war protests.
And you may not realize it, but protesting the genocide in Palestine is actually all three of those combined.
So please have a healthy respect of just how far the system will go to silence you.
All power, I'm proud of you.
Keep going.